Finding Aid for the UNITE HERE Records LSC.2325
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Local 814 Records, 1950-2003
  - Subseries 2.1: Kurt Petersen files, circa 1980s-2004
    - Miramar performance evaluations (3 folders), (1993-1997) (Box 11, Folder 55-57)
    - Miramar petition #1, (undated) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Miramar propaganda, (1990s) (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Miramar report, articles and ephemera, (1997 Dec 15, 1998 May 4, 1997, 2000, undated) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Miramar stickers, (undated) (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Miramar team meetings, (1995 Dec 15) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Miramar - Tolentini hearing reports, (1998 May 15) (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Miramar vote, (2000) (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Miramar wage/hour claim issues, (1998) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Miramar Ulysses arbitrator report pages, (undated) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Miramar union busting, (1996-1997) (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Miramar union busting, (1997) (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Miramar: union's objections of election (3 copies), (1997) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Miramar victories press, (1998-1999) (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - New buyer Miramar, (1998-1999 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - New model of Labor Relations in the San Francisco Hotel Industry (A), 1994 March (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - NLRB charges dismissed, (1997 Jun 27) (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Noel Rodriguez arrest, (1996) (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Nonviolent action handbook, (1995, 2000) (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Organizing and Roman Catholic teaching, (1980s-1990s) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Organizing leads, (undated) (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Casa del Mar employee handbook; Radisson Huntley Hotel employee handbook.
    - Organizing tactics / strategy, (1996 Feb, 1997-1998) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Organizing training, (1995, 2000 Aug, undated) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - PERI Economic Analysis of Santa Monica Living Wage Proposal, (2000 Aug) (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
    - Petersen - Miramar declarations and correspondence re. collective bargaining and worker grievances, (1995-1997) (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Petersen - Miramar NLRB, (undated) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Pilot project, (2001 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - PKF Consulting, (1991-1995) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Planning process 1997, (1992 Nov 2, 1996 Jan-Feb, 1997 Sept 30 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Precinct walking, (1996) (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Press Viceroy, (2000) (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Pritkin Center - Casa del Mar, (1997) (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Proposition KK, (2000) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Proposition KK and Santa Monica election materials and data, (1998, 2000 and undated) (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Rabbi Comess-Daniels statement re. Miramar Sheraton, (undated) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Recent unfair wages cases, (1995-1999) (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Regent Beverley Wilshire, (1999 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Room for Improvement report, (2002 Sept) (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Sample employer objections, (1997) (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - San Francisco and Las Vegas hotel workers studies, (2002 May 16 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Santa Monica analysis, (1999) (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Santa Monica campaign maps and walk rap, (1998) (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Santa Monica city council elections, (1998) (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Santa Monica city election training, (1999) (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Santa Monica election, (1996) (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Santa Monica election, (2002) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Santa Monica election articles, (1998 Nov) (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Santa Monica election candidates 11/98, (1998) (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Santa Monica living wage ordinance, (1998-1999) (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Santa Monica living wage ordinance, (2000) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Santa Monica municipal election, (1998) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Santa Monica municipal elections timesheets, (1996) (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Santa Monica news clippings and 1997 Economic Impact of Tourism in Santa Monica, (1996-1998) (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Santa Monica reality tour, (1999 Feb 6 and undated) (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Santa Monica Renters' Rights, (2000) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - SEIU training on direct action 1995, (undated) (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Sheraton Miramar Hotel Vote Union Yes petition (anti Carlos Ortiz), (undated) (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Sky Chefs management access fight, (1995) (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Sky Chefs organizing campaign, (1994) (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - SMART / Miramar election, (1997) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - SMART 2002, (2001-2002) (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - SMART Living Wage Kickoff program, (1999) (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Statements and hearing reports, (1997-1998) (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Subpoena information, (1999) (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Sweeney to political council, (1996 Dec) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Tax Day action chants and marshall training outline, (undated) (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Termination, (1996-2000 and undated) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - TIDC, (1995-1996) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Trustees - Santa Monica College victory clipping, (1999 May) (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Union propaganda Local 2, (1990s) (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Viscount, (1991 and undated) (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Vote Union Yes flyer, (undated) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - WH Smith at LAX, (1999-2000) (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Wilshire Blvd. development, (1999) (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Working Conditions and Health of San Francisco Hotel Room Cleaners report to HERE, (1999 Aug) (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Wyndham / LAX employee list, (1999 Apr 8) (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Wyndham grievances, (1997-1999) (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2.2: Tom Walsh files, circa 1980s-circa 1990s, 2001
    Contains a small amount flyers, clippings, publications, and memos related to local union organizing campaigns, immigration reform, and health reform, among other matters of concern to Local 814.
    - ACLU The Human Costs of Employer Sanctions (Recommendations for GAO's Third Report to Congress Under the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986), (1989 Nov) (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Action flyers, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - AFL-CIO memos and ephemera, (1993-1994) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Airport unions coalition, (1992-1993) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Alcazar vs Sheraton La Reina court transcript, (1991 Mar 19) (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Bartender training, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Board of Supervisors Los Angeles County thank you re town hall meeting, (1993 Jun 23) (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Clinton health reform, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Community Development Commission Los Angeles Revitalization Zone, (1992) (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Complaints against Sizzler Restaurant, (1992) (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Flyers and ephemera, (early 1990s) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - HERE Local 2 HIV/AIDS, (1994) (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Holiday Inn LAX, (early 1990s) (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Hyatt and Wyndham, (1995) (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Immigration, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Justice For Janitors organizing community supporter letters, (1994) (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Las Vegas organizing, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - LAX organizing surveys, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Lennox organizing, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Multi-Cultural Tourism Development Conference, (1994) (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - News clippings with mentions of Walsh or events in which he was involved, (late 1980s, 1990s, 2001) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - News clippings, (1993-1994) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - NLRB elections statistics and notice of filing of petition, (1992, 1994) (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Organizer's Guide to Victory (An), (1992 Nov 15) (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Radisson grievances and employee communication, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Radisson newsletters and flyers, (1993 and undated) (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Sheraton La Reina union busting, (1980s) (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Union publications and flyers, (early 1990s) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - United Mine Workers of America strike, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Wilson Center research, (1993) (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2.3: Bill Granfield files, 1988-1997, 1999
    Materials are mostly related to the Airport Marina Hotel (Airtel) and information concerning organizing projects, such as Sheraton Hotel, Viscount Hotel, and an LAX Organizing Project thesis by Fred A. Seavey, among others. Additionally included are a small number of training materials for shop stewards.
    Files are arranged alphabetically.
    - Agreement by and between Artel Hotel Inc. and HERE Local 814 (Effective February 1, 1989), (undated) (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Airport Marina committee election, (undated) (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Airport Marina committee rosters, (1991, 1992 and undated) (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Airport Marina comprehensive, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Airport Marina contract meeting flyers, (1992) (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Airport Marina correspondence, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Airport Marina employee rosters, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Airport Marina Hotel (Airtel) arbitration opinion and award transcript, (1991 Jul 24) (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Airport Marina Jesus Ceja, (1991 Oct) (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Airport Marina Jorge Aragon, (1991 Oct) (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Airport Marina originals - flyers, (undated) (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Airport Marina ULP, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Atlas Hotel and NLRB answer to complaint and ephemera, (1992) (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - California Labor Press Directory, (1988) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - California State Employees Association anti-union activity, (1993) (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Carson International and Local 450 contract, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Caterair LAX, circa 1991 (Box 18, Folder 58)
      Petition regarding decertification and a photocopy of agreement between Marriott In-Flight Services Shoppes 308, 380 and 687 and International Brotherhood of Teamsters Chauffeurs, Sales Drivers and Helpers Union Local 572.
    - Chelsea Catering Corporation - LAX, (1988) (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Chief shop stewards training materials, (1995) (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Children's Hospital Orange County thrift shop workers employee discount policy, (1992 Sept 17) (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Christmas party invitation, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Church, community, etc., (1988-1991) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Embassy Suites employee standards of conduct, (1993) (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - HERE / SEIU organizing charts, (1995 May 4) (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Holiday Inn employee information, monthly sales reports, and market share analysis, (1993) (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Hollywood Park Casino articles, committee building and strategy meeting records, (1994) (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Interns - CORO fellowship, (1993-1995) (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Iowa riverboats industry information, (1991) (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Iowa riverboats organizing, (1999) (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - L.A. organizing project, (1988) (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Labor, circa 1989-1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      With Orange County Organizing Committee meeting minutes (1989 July and August, 1991 March); AFL-CIO booklets; flyers and ephemera.
    - Language training programs, (1989-1990) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Las Vegas labor shortage, (1989) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Las Vegas Project, (1990-1991) (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - LAX office administration, (1989-1990) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - LAX Organizing Project by Fred A. Seavey, MA thesis and notes, (1994) (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Lennox organizing meeting flyers, (1993 Jun 24) (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Local 11 L.A., (1988-1991) (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Local 217 Connecticut, (1989) (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Local 28 Mission Foods, (1991) (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Local 30 San Diego, (1989-1990) (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Local 681 door-to-door materials, (undated) (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Local 681 Long Beach, (1989 and undated) (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Media contact list, (undated) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Organizer internship training materials, (1995-1997) (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Organizing Women Workers, (1997 Apr 11-12) (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Radisson family budget survey, (1993) (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Report forms: week, month, mileage, (undated) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Sample contract surveys, (undated) (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - San Diego Convention Center, (1990) (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Sheraton Grande action preparation, (1994) (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Sheraton LAX follow-up, (1991 Jan 19 and undated) (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Sheraton LAX planning, (1990-1992) (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Shop stewards training materials, (1989) (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Shop stewards training materials, (1990s) (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - UCLA Labor Center, (1993) (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Union Voice publications, (1992, 1993) (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Viscount - Inez Joseph, (1990-1991) (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Viscount Hotel LAX: post-election poll '92, (undated) (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Viscount Hotel union election Activistas, (1991 and undated) (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Subseries 2.4: Victor Valenzuela files, circa 1950s-1993
    Includes a small number of files related to the Bay Area Restaurant Association, NLRB, and contracts, and miscellany.
    - Address book, (undated) (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Bay Area Restaurant Association, (1950-1968) (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Bay Area Restaurant master agreement and addendums, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Business Manager Reports, (1995 Jan-1995 Dec) (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Canteen contracts, circa early 1980s (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Casa Escobar contracts, (1965-1988) (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Department of Labor-Management Standards, (1990-1993) (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Excerpts from Organizing and the NLRB Law, (1968-1969) (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Grievance forms, circa early 1990s (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Local 814 bylaws, 1986 February (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - NLRB Representation and Decertification Elections Statistics, (1995 Apr) (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Round Table Restaurant correspondence, (1968-1988) (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Santa Monica culinary welfare fund, (1984) (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Valenzuela miscellany, (circa early 1990s) (Box 19, Folder 31)
      Membership card and monthly stamp book belonging to Catherine Regensburger; form letter from Barbara Boxer; membership meeting document regarding Sky Chefs employees; and other items.
  - Subseries 2.5: Gary Guthman files, 1988-1990
    Includes Manhattan Beach Radisson flyers.
    - Manhattan Beach Radisson flyers, (1988-1990) (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Subseries 2.6: Photographs and ephemera, 1996-2002
    Includes Local 814 photograph album and posters.
    Files are unarranged.
    - Posters that appear related to Local 11, circa 2000s (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Local 814 photograph album, 1996-2002 (Box 45, Folder 1)
- Series 3: Local 681 Records, 1920-1994, 1999-2004; 1920-1980
  The bulk of the series comprises periodical publications and union booklets related to the work of Local 681. Periodical publications include Serving America, The Mixer and Server, and Catering Industry Employee, (The Mixer and Server continued publication under title of Catering Industry Employee starting in October 1929), among others. Union booklets document employee wage scale and working conditions, benefits, and constitutions and by-laws. Additionally there are two photographs albums, clippings, and ephemera.
  The series is in original order.
  - First Annual Convention, California State Council of Culinary Workers Bartenders and Hotel Service Employees, Long Beach - oversize photograph, (1942 Sept 19) (Box 55)
  - The Mixer and Server periodical (Volumes 29 and 32), (1920, 1923) (Box 21)
    See also Catering Industry Employee.
  - The Mixer and Server periodical (Volume 37), (1928) (Box 22)
  - The Mixer and Server and The Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volume 38), (1929) (Box 22)
    Volume contains both titles because of title change of publication of The Mixer and Server to The Catering Industry Employee in October 1929.
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 39-41), (1930-1932) (Box 23)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 43-45), (1934-1936) (Box 24)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 46-47), (1937-1938) (Box 25)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 48-50), (1939-1941) (Box 26)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 51-53), (1942-1944) (Box 27)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 54-56), (1945-1947) (Box 28)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 57-59), (1948-1950) (Box 29)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 60-62), (1951-1953) (Box 30)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 63-65), (1954-1956) (Box 31)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 66-68), (1957-1959) (Box 32)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 69-71), (1960-1962) (Box 33)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 72-74), (1963-1965) (Box 34)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 75-77), (1966-1968) (Box 35)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 78-80), (1969-1971) (Box 36)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 81-84), (1972-1975) (Box 37)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 85-88), (1976-1979) (Box 38)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 89-90, 92), (1980-1981, 1983) (Box 39)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 93-96), (1984-1987) (Box 40)
  - Catering Industry Employee periodical (Volumes 97-99), (1989-1990) (Box 41)
  - Serving America, Hotel-Bar-Restaurant news, Long Beach and Orange County periodical, (1965-1992) (Box 20, Folder 15-28)
  - Serving America, Hotel-Bar-Restaurant news, Long Beach periodical, (1947-1948) (Box 20, Folder 5-15)
  - Serving America Issued By Culinary Alliance, Local No. 681 periodical, (1942) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Union Voice/Voz Unida newsletter, (1993-1994, 1999-2000) (Box 20, Folder 29-30)
  - The Efficient Waitress Manual booklet, (1945) (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Bartenders International Union withdrawal card, (1948 Nov 11) (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees' International Alliance Bartenders' International League of America Report for October, 1899 of the Secretary Treasurer - printed ephemera, (1899 Oct) (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Long Beach Hotel and Restaurant Workers Local Union Number 681 Second Annual Greatest Show On Earth program, (1938 Jun 20) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Union booklets mostly regarding wage scale and working conditions, (1937, 1940s-1980s, 1992) (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
  - Union booklets mostly regarding benefits, (1945, 1953, 1960s-1980) (Box 42, Folder 8-16)
  - Union booklets mostly regarding constitutions and by-laws, (1921, 1936, 1940s-1980s) (Box 42, Folder 17-25)
  - Union booklets mostly regarding wage scale and working conditions for specific businesses, (1950s-1980s) (Box 43)
    Appear to be identified with specific Long Beach and/or Orange County business names. Some locations annotated and/or printed on booklets, such as Anaheim Bowl; Arnold's Farm House; Aztec Bowl; Buttery; Century Bowl; Chris & Pitts BBQ; Dal Rae; Del Rio Lanes; Dimitres Restaurant; El Adobe; Francois; Glider Inn; Heck's; Highland Bowl; Hillview Bowl; Huntington Lanes; International City Club; Keona; Long Beach Harbor Inn; Loyd's; Marina Lanes; Mike's Restaurant; New Method School of Bartending; Phillip's Chicken Pie; Pioneer Bowl; Plaza Lanes; Premier Lanes; Rossmore Bowl; Sierra; Stem Room; Sut's; Tee Cee's; Two J's Café; and Village Inn.
  - Union booklets mostly regarding wage scale and working conditions for specific businesses, (1940s-1990s) (Box 44)
    Appear to be identified with specific Long Beach and/or Orange County business names. Some locations annotated and.or printed on booklets, such as Alfred's; Anaheim Hilton and Towers; Anaheim Stadium and Anaheim Convention Center; Boyle's; Captain's Quarters; Concession Air, Inc.; Daly's Cocktails; Disneyland; Evan's Family Restaurant; Hilton At The Park; Hof's Hut; Hubert's Cafeteria; Huntington Hotel; It'l Do; Johnnie W. Miller Sandwich Company; Kettle, Little's; Los Alamitos Race Course; Lucy's; Mannings; Nationwide Food Services; Orbit Coffee Shop; Phil's Brite Spot; The Phone Booth; Poor Richard's; Press Club; Revere House; Ric A Box; Royal Inn Hotel of Anaheim; Flagship International (Sky Chefs); Steak 'n' Stuff Restaurant; and The Trap.
  - Union booklets and pamphlets (assorted), (1971, 1976, undated) (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - News clippings (originals and photocopies), (1999-2004) (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
    From the Los Angeles Times and Orange County Register, among others.
  - Officers Local 681 (1953-1955) oversize photograph, (undated) (Box 55)
  - Photograph album, (undated) (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Photograph album and union pins, (undated) (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, (1950, 1954-1956) (Box 20, Folder 1)
    St. Jude Hospital citation; Culinary Alliance membership to Convention and Visitor's Bureau of Long Beach both presented to Local 681; and AFL conference attendance certificates for Kathryn Arnold and Jack Arnold.
  - City of Hope Medical Center recognition to Culinary Local 681 - plaque, (1972) (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Vote Yes (empty binder), (undated) (Box 51, Folder 2)